When is a pineapple not a pineapple?
When it's a grenade!
Now. it's a party!
Grenade!
We are losing this fight.
Not a fight anymore. boss.
This new guy is making it a war.
Where the hell is Thorne?
Detective. this will be a lot smoother
if you’d just make my client an offer.
Scare tactics won’t get you
where you want to go.
This guy.
Name.
He's running things. right?
Workin' for Thorne?
Or did he take over?
-Still not hearing an offer.
-Your guy tried to murder a witness!
Allegedly. detective. Allegedly.
He destroyed over a million dollars
worth of property.
I’m saying he doesn’t get an offer.
Suits me.
'Cause even if you made one.
I wouldn't take it.
Okay. Looks like we're done here.
-Whose side are you on. Gordon?
-The law’s side. Detective Flass.
You know. the thing you’re supposed
to protect and serve.
I'm no rat.
You of all people should know that.
You little piece of shit!
-What the hell? Renee!
-Hey! Ease up. Flass. Jesus!
Guard!
Hey. Flass.
Next time you talk to Mr. Thorne.
tell him to buy you a new suit.
I’m so sorry for your loss.
Mrs. Fuller.
Let me know if your family needs anything.
This department needed Fuller.
He was an honest officer.
and I don’t have many of those.
This one's the real question mark.
He started popping up
after Thorne’s arrest.
Since then. gangland murders
are triple what they were last year.
there have been two bombings.
and we only barely interrupted
a kidnapping this week.
One of Thorne’s lieutenants
making his own moves.
Could be. or Thorne’s finally lost it.
and this is his revenge on the city
for putting him on trial.
The one guy who might know
for sure isn’t talking.
Mark Desmond.
Since Thorne’s trial.
Desmond’s the only member of the gang
we’ve brought in alive.
And he’d rather spend the next twenty
in Blackgate than be known as a snitch.
He needs someone to confide in.
Someone he can trust.
That leaves out just about everyone
in Gotham. Unless you have a...
The son of a bitch is gonna
get us all killed.
He let Rocco get gunned down like a dog!
I don’t like Eddie anymore than you do.
but Mr. Thorne left him in charge.
If we go against Eddie.
we go against Mr. Thorne.
-And we owe him better than that.
-And where the hell is Mr. Thorne?
Coney Island. Timbuktu. it don’t matter!
Eddie’s in charge. The end.
I'm telling you.
we need new leadership.
You got trouble. baby.
The tie?
You’re the one who picked it.
Not the tie!
Rocco getting killed ain’t sitting right
with the gang.
Ah. damn whiners!
They’re getting a bigger share
of the take. ain’t they?
Yeah. but Eddie. if Mr. Thorne
doesn’t come back soon...
What? Think I can't handle it?
No baby. never.
I’m just worried is all. About you.
But maybe talk with the boys now? For me?
Just so I don’t worry.
Hey. boys.
I understand there have been
some complaints.
Tony? Vic?
Uh. yeah. We. uh...
some of us got. you know. concerns.
You do. huh?
Well. let’s hear ‘em.
These jobs we been pullin’.
they pay out good.
nobody’s saying they don’t. but...
-they’re risky.
-No risk. no reward. Am I right?
Maybe they're a little too risky.
you know?
Like. maybe if we wasn’t
bracing the cops so much.
Rocco wouldn’t be dead.
Could be worse.
He could be in some cell.
getting worked over by cops
‘til he spills like a broken milk bottle.
Rocco was no rat!
Anybody's a rat.
you put on the right screws!
It’s like sitting in a leaky boat.
But you know how to fix a leaky boat.
Vicky boy?
How's that?
Now...
Anybody else got... concerns?
Speakin' of leaks.
I hear the badges have been visiting
my old buddy Dez at Blackgate.
I’m gonna need to put a plug in that too.
This thing's goin' south. Johnny.
Nah. We’re getting clear of this. see.
Even if we gotta drop
a couple coppers on the way.
The boss don’t like us mixing it up
with the police. Johnny!
To hell with the boss.
He’d been holding back our cut.
I’m gonna take my due and give him his.
The paperwork is ready.
Your transfer from stately Wayne Manor
to Blackgate Prison
will take place in an hour.
I trust that the legend I prepared for you
was satisfactory.
Master Bruce?
Where are you from?
Detroit.
Rap sheet?
Robbery. Fraud. Larceny.
Looking for a situation
driving for the mob.
The hell is this?
New roommate for ya. Dez.
Name's Matches.
Matches Malone.
Ah. who cares?
Get used to it.
What the hell happened here?
He scuffed my shoes.
He scuffed your... get 'em outta here!
"He scuffed my shoes."
Brother. you are a caution.
Yeah. what can I say? I like a good shine.
Name's Dez.
You said. "Matches." before?
Yeah. Matches Malone.
Sorry if I was a jerk last night.
Forget about it.
I feel like you and me met
before. sometime. On the outside.
Not likely. I'm new in town.
And already in Blackgate?
Brother. you know how to find trouble.
Better than trouble lookin' for me.
What?
Maybe we oughta drift.
Right behind ya.
Nice. You got a head on you.
Matches Malone.
Hey. I’m not taking any bruises
I don’t buy.
Brother. I sure got lucky
getting you for a cellie.
-Let me tell ya.
-Me. not so much.
Who put the target on your back?
What target?
Two times some guys zeroed in on you.
You're marked.
Sure. if they got a screw loose.
Anybody messes with me.
they answer to my boss.
-And he runs Gotham.
-Hey. maybe I did get lucky.
I came to Gotham looking for a situation
with whoever runs this burg.
Yeah? Okay.
Well. maybe we can talk about... that.
Get these clowns back to their cell.
It don't make sense. These mooks know
better than to put hands on me.
I’m protected.
-By Rupert Thorne.
-Sure. sure. Wait. You heard of him?
Everyone in Detroit has heard of Thorne.
If that’s your boss. you wanna reach out.
-Let him know what’s going on in here.
-It’s Mister Thorne.
And you don’t reach out to Mister Thorne.
He reaches out to you.
Well. somebody better do something.
Sooner or later. whoever’s out to nail you
is gonna get lucky too.
Quiet in there!
Lights out!
Drink up. baby. We got two bottles
of Silver Lining right here.
Oh. damn. here comes a rain cloud.
Better be good.
This bubbly goes flat. and I will...
Not... dead?
How the hell is he not dead?
It's almost a week since the hit went out!
What can I say. boss? He made a friend.
Friend?
Dez doesn't have friends!
He's got... me!
I want him dead. you get me?!
Dead! Dead!
Dead!
Any questions?
I don't get it.
I’ve never sat in the jug this long.
Usually. I get bailed out in a day.
Two. max.
Somebody has you marked.
Who’d you piss off?
You talking to the bulls
when you shouldn’t?
You calling me a snitch?!
I ain’t no snitch. Matches.
Okay. okay. Easy. I’m just saying...
Yeah? Well. don't.
You know what? Drift.
I need to think.
Suit yourself.
Put ‘em both in the hole.
Matches?
You over there. Matches?
I'm here.
What you did in the yard...
Thanks.
Thank me by gettin' me a gig
once I'm out of here.
Thing is.
Mr. Thorne won’t take just anyone.
You need like a skill.
Bergduff heist in Jersey. Two years back.
-That was you?
-I was the wheelman.
Damn.
Big job.
Then they tried to cheat me out of my cut.
Got ugly. But I got my due.
And so did they.
You sound like this guy I know
from Chicago.
Met him in juvie.
Became bosom buddies.
Got into so much trouble.
He shot up so many joints.
they started calling him "The Riddler."
I got him in with Mr. Thorne.
and now. he's practically runnin' things.
"The Riddler." huh?
That sounds like a guy I need to meet.
Can't introduce you if I'm dead.
You said it. Matches.
Sooner or later.
these bastards are gonna get lucky.
You gotta get out of here. Dez.
I'm already working on a plan.
I figure if we can...
-How the hell...
-I got skills.
-Jeez. you sure do.
-You comin' or not?
Go!
Hurry.
Take that. ya damned screws!
Who’s top of the world now?
Okay. I held up my end.
What about your friends?
Sure. buddy. sure.
A wheelman like you is gonna fit right in.
Beats the hell out of
those prison monkey-suits.
And they fit.
Thorne controls these warehouses.
Always need some new gear
if a job gets bloody.
And here's Eddie now.
Eddie!
I was blissfully listening to the radio
when some yutz breaks in
on my favorite program.
talking about an escape from Blackgate.
So I ask myself. who would have the brass
to even try to slide outta Blackgate?
Then it hits me. Dez.
Who else?
I had to blow out of there. Eddie.
Some guys tried to ice me and...
Ice you?
Who in the world would want
to ice you. Dez?
You’re salt of the earth.
We gotta tell Mr. Thorne
people ain’t following the rules.
Yeah. sure.
Thing is. he’s still... on sabbatical.
I’m running things.
Who's this?
Matches. He’s a pal.
Got me outta the jug.
I can vouch for him.
Oh. you can?
Matches. huh?
You some kind of a breakout king. Matches?
Not a king.
Just a wheelman who’s looking for a...
Matches. Stupid name.
You still got good timing. Dez.
Just about to go on a spree.
Eddie’s getting me a new necklace.
Vic took the night off.
and we could use another set of hands.
You in?
Yeah. Eddie. Sure.
You bet.
Pennyworth. it's me.
I need the car.
This won't take long.
What's baby in the mood for tonight?
Dammit!
This stinks!
Four times. I try to ice you in the jug.
Four times. you skate!
Eddie?
Then you bust out
with your new tag-along-buddy.
and the Batman just magically
shows up on the spot?
Somebody squealed!
You know what happens to squealers.
don’t you. Dez?
No.
I ain’t no squealer!
Not anymore.
Matches?
That you?
Of course it is.
You're the Batman.
Funny. huh.
Me and Eddie go back so far. but...
turns out my best friend in the world...
was the goddamn Batman.
His name is Edward Nygma.
AKA The Riddler.
Impulsive. Reckless. Highly unpredictable.
His kind of chaos can spin out of control.
It pains me to say this.
but your job might become simpler
when Thorne returns to the helm.
At least we know the identity
of the man who has replaced him.
And he’d be behind bars if Matches...
if I hadn’t hesitated.
Some have said that empathy
is the sign of a healthy mind.
Will that be all. sir?
Very good. sir.